That Time I Got Reincarnated as a Slime
So, what do we do?
（スライム）
で どうする？
Episode 2: Meeting the Goblins
Hmm?
About the Unlimited Imprisonment
seal that hero put on you.
（スライム）
勇者がかけた
無限牢獄(ろうごく)の封印
I feel bad knowing my friend's
been sealed here for 300 years.
友達が
300年も封印されたままなんて
かわいそうだからな
You...
（ヴェルドラ）お前…
Don't give me those puppy dog eyes!
（スライム）
そんな うるうると
見つめられても…
It'd be one thing coming from
a cute girl, but a dragon?
かわいい女の子なら ともかく
ドラゴンに
If you have a way to get
me out, I'd appreciate it.
（ヴェルドラ）
脱出方法があるなら ありがたいが
Th-The thing is...
じっ 実はな…
あと100年も待たずに
I wouldn't have lasted another 100
years before my magic ran out.
我の魔力は
底をつくところだったのだ
I keep losing more and more magicules...
魔素(まそ)は漏れ続けておるし…
So that's why this cave
is so rich in magicules,
（スライム）
だから この洞窟は魔素が濃くて
and there are so many
valuable herbs and ore.
貴重な薬草や鉱石が出来たのか
What happens when your magic runs out?
魔力が底をつくと どうなる？
It's not a huge deal.
（ヴェルドラ）大したことはない
It's not?
（スライム）大したことないの？
（ヴェルドラ）
フンッ 朽ち果てるだけのことよ
I'll just die, that's all.
I... I see...
（スライム）そ… そうか
After all these years of
isolation, you just die, huh?
長い孤独のあとに
朽ち果てるだけか…
Might as well try this.
ふむ 試してみるか
Great Sage, use Predator to consume
the Unlimited Imprisonment.
“捕食者”で無限牢獄を捕食しろ
Failed.
（大賢者）
失敗しました
I guess it won't be that easy.
（スライム）
そう簡単には いかないか
See? It's impossible.
（ヴェルドラ）無理であろう？
（スライム）
ん〜 どうにかならないか？
Isn't there anything we can do?
Examining the possibilities.
（大賢者）
可能性を検討します
Hey! Don't just keep
talking to your own skill!
（ヴェルドラ）おい！
自分のスキルとばかり
話(はなし)するでない
Old man...
（スライム）おっさん…
Examination completed.
（大賢者）
検討終了
可能性としましては…
Possibilities include...
Uh-huh.
（スライム）
ふむふむ…
なるほど なるほど
I see, I see.
It's only a possibility, but...
あくまで可能性だが…
She says if we can analyze the Unlimited
Imprisonment from both inside and out,
無限牢獄の内側と外側から
解析できれば
we might be able to remove it.
解除できるかもってさ
Oh?
（ヴェルドラ）ほう…
Wait, but... I can't analyze
it from the inside.
いや しかし 内側からといっても
My skills are sealed along with me,
so I can't use them.
我のスキルは
我と共に封印されて使えぬぞ
If you can just give me the data,
I can analyze it out here.
（スライム）
情報だけ よこしてくれれば
解析は こっちでやるから
But that could take some time.
（ヴェルドラ）
しかし それには時間がかかろう
Are you sure you want to
stay in here that long?
お前だって
ずっと ここにいていいのか？
W-Well, not that I mind, but...
ま… まあ 我は別に構わぬが
Good point...
（スライム）
そうだな
俺も せっかくだから
Since I'm here, I'd like to search
for others from my homeland.
同郷の者を探したりしたい
（ヴェルドラ）そうか…
I see...
So here's a suggestion.
（スライム）それで 提案だ
（ヴェルドラ）ハッ… 提案とな？
A suggestion?
Want to get in my stomach?
（スライム）
俺の胃袋に入らないか？
I'll use my skills, Great Sage and Predator,
to analyze Unlimited Imprisonment
（スライム）
俺のスキル
“大賢者”と“捕食者”で
無限牢獄の解析を行い
while you try to destroy it from the inside.
内部からは
ヴェルドラが破壊を試みる
You'll be quarantined in my
stomach, so you won't disappear.
胃袋の中では隔離されるので
消滅するおそれもない
どうだ？
What do you say?
ハ〜ッハハハハ！
That sounds interesting! Please, do it!
（ヴェルドラ）
それは面白い
ぜひ やってくれ！
I'll entrust my entirety to you!
お前に 我の全てを委ねる！
Are you sure you want to
believe me that easily?
（スライム）
そんなに簡単に信じていいのか？
Of course!
（ヴェルドラ）無論だ！
It sounds more fun to break through
Unlimited Imprisonment together
ここで
お前が帰ってくるのを待つよりも
than to wait here alone until you come back!
２人で無限牢獄を破るほうが
面白そうだ
Right...
（スライム）
そうか １人じゃなく２人か…
Better two than one...
Sounds great!
いいじゃないか！
Yes!
（ヴェルドラ）うむ
（スライム）あ…
（ヴェルドラ）フン
O-Okay, I'll use Predator to—
（スライム）
じゃ… じゃあ
今から“捕食者”で…
（ヴェルドラ）
ちょ… ちょっと待て
W-Wait a moment!
Before we start, I'll give you a name.
（ヴェルドラ）
その前に
お前に名前を付けてやろう
You can give me one, too.
お前も 我に名を付けよ
Huh?
It will engrave onto our souls
the fact that we are equals.
（ヴェルドラ）
同格ということを魂に刻むのだ
It'll be what humans call a "family name,"
人間でいう
ファミリーネームみたいなものだが
but the name I give you will
grant you divine protection.
我が お前に名付けるのは
“加護”になる
You are still nameless, so you'll
become a monster with a name.
お前は まだ“名無し”だから
名持ちの魔物の仲間入りができるぞ
（スライム）
むむ 名持ちの魔物か… いいな！
A monster with a name, huh?
That sounds good!
Doesn't it?
（ヴェルドラ）いいだろう？
Give me a cool name!
かっこいいのを頼むぞ
Same to you!
（スライム）そっちもな
A cool name...
かっこいい… そうだなあ
Let's see...
The Storm Dragon, Veldora...
暴風竜ヴェルドラ…
Storm, huh?
“暴風”か…
And... what's another
word for a storm, again?
英語で“暴風”
嵐は… 何だっけ？
Storm... sounds kinda weird.
ストーム？　いまいちだな
あっ テンペスト！
Tempest!
What do you think of "Tempest"?
“テンペスト”なんて どうかな？
What?!
なにい！　テンペストだと〜？
Tempest, you say?!
D-Don't like it?
（スライム）ダ… ダメか？
It sounds fantastic!
（ヴェルドラ）すばらしい響きだ！
As of today, I am Veldora Tempest!
今日から我は
ヴェルドラ＝テンペストだ〜！
（スライム）
き… 気に入ったのかよ
Y-You like it?
And I will grant you the name "Rimuru."
（ヴェルドラ）
そして お前には
〝リムル〞の名を与える
Rimuru...
（スライム）
リムル… 悪くないな
Not bad.
You will be Rimuru Tempest!
（ヴェルドラ）
リムル＝テンペストを名乗るがよい
At that moment, something
changed deep in my soul.
（スライム）
その瞬間
魂の奥底で何かが変化した
Rimuru Tempest
The name "Rimuru Tempest"
had become engraved upon it.
リムル＝テンペストの名が
魂に刻まれたのだ
（リムル）
俺は… リムル＝テンペスト！
I am... Rimuru Tempest.
Rimuru...
（ヴェルドラ）リムル
Veldora Tempest...
（リムル）ヴェルドラ＝テンペスト
Okay, I'm going to eat you now.
（リムル）じゃあ 今から食うけど
Break out of that
Unlimited Imprisonment already!
さっさと
無限牢獄から脱出してこいよ！
（ヴェルドラ）
フフフッ 任せておけ
Leave it to me.
I will see you face-to-face in no time!
そんなに待たせずに
お前と相まみえようぞ
All right!
（リムル）
よし　ユニークスキル“捕食者”！
Unique skill: Predator!
That ended far too soon.
（リムル）実に あっけなかった
I was just talking with him a moment ago...
今まで しゃべっていたのに…
Unlimited Imprisonment
Would you like to analyze the unique
skill Unlimited Imprisonment?
（大賢者）
ユニークスキル“無限牢獄”の
解析を行いますか？
Yes. Please do it.
（リムル）イエス　頼んだぞ
A great tremor rocked the world on this day.
（リムル）
この日 世界に激震が走った
The disappearance of the
Storm Dragon Veldora,
天災級モンスターである
暴風竜ヴェルドラの消滅が
a Catastrophe-class monster, was confirmed.
確認されたのだ
The cave where Veldora had been sealed
was in the Great Forest of Jura.
ヴェルドラが封印されていた洞窟は
ジュラと呼ばれる
大森林の中にあった
In the area of the Great Forest
of Jura are several countries.
ジュラの大森林の周辺には
いくつもの国があった
Barren Lands
The Western Provinces
The Eastern Plains
Great Forest of Jura
Canaat Mountains
Kingdom of Falmus
Kingdom of Blumund
Sealed Cave
Lake Siss
In one of them, the Kingdom of Blumund...
（リムル）
そんな国のひとつ
ブルムンド王国では…
Kingdom of Blumund
（ベルヤード）
暴風竜ヴェルドラの件
聞いているだろう？
Minister Baron Veryard
You've heard about the
Storm Dragon Veldora, yes?
Of course I have.
（フューズ）
もちろんですよ
Guild Master Fuze
（ベルヤード）フンッ
I should have expected
as much of a guild master.
さすがはギルドマスター
と言っておこうか
では ギルドとしての対策を
聞かせてくれんか？
So, can you tell me what measures
the guild intends to take?
We have no plans to take
any particular action.
（フューズ）
特に何かを行う予定はありません
ヴェルドラが
消滅したということは
The disappearance of Veldora is predicted
to galvanize the monsters!
魔物の活性化が
予想されるのだぞ！
ハア…
不可侵領域だった暴風竜の
封印されていた場所を通って
There is a chance that the Eastern
Kingdom will advance through the
東の帝国が動きだす可能性があるな
previously impassable region that
the Storm Dragon was sealed in.
If they get through that forest,
（ベルヤード）
あの森を抜けられたら
ジュラの大森林周辺の国家など
the provinces surrounding
the Great Forest of Jura
瞬く間に
帝国の支配下に置かれてしまう
will fall under the empire's
rule, in the blink of an eye.
疲れた顔だ
ちゃんと寝てるのか？
You look tired.
Are you getting enough sleep?
As a favor to an old friend,
幼なじみの よしみだ
俺が個人的に調査だけはしてやる
I'll conduct an investigation personally.
ジュラの大森林の様子と
帝国の動向は探ってみるよ
I'll look into the state of the Great Forest
of Jura and the kingdom's movements.
Thank you. Please see to it.
すまん　頼む
The chaos in the surrounding
countries since noticing
（リムル）
ヴェルドラの消滅を感じた各国が
that Veldora disappeared was
like a disturbed hornet's nest.
蜂の巣をつついたような大騒ぎに
なっているとは
Of course, Rimuru had no way to know this.
もちろん
リムルは知るよしもなく…
How many days has it been
since I ate Veldora?
（リムル）
ヴェルドラを食ってから
何日過ぎただろう
I wandered around everywhere,
trying to get out of the cave.
俺は洞窟を出ようと
あちこちを さまよっていた
I gobbled up all the herbs
and ores I came across
目についた草や鉱物を食いまくって
体内に ためながら
to store them in my body.
（リムル）
♪ ふ〜ふふ〜ん
ふふ〜ん ふ〜ふ〜ん
Water Movement
Skill: Water Movement acquired.
（大賢者）
スキル“水流移動”を獲得しました
Acquired
— Water Blade  —
Skill: Water Blade acquired.
（大賢者）
スキル
〝水刃(すいじん)〞を獲得しました
The acquired skills Water Pressure Propulsion,
Water Movement, and Water Blade
スキル“水圧推進”
スキル“水流移動”
Water Pressure
Propulsion
Water Movement
Water Blade
スキル“水刃”を
獲得したことにより
Water Blade
Water Pressure
Propulsion
Water Movement
Water Blade
Water Pressure
Propulsion
Water Movement
Combine
combine to evolve into extra
skill, Water Manipulation.
エクストラスキル“水操作”へと
統合進化しました
Water Manipulation
Evolution
I tried out lots of things
and gained some new skills.
（リムル）
いろいろ試して
いくつものスキルを得た
And then... I found the one!
そして 俺は出会った！
The one bound to me by
the red thread of fate!
赤い糸で結ばれた運命の人…
Except it wasn't.
ではなく
Black Serpent Appeared
（リムル）
怖(こえ)え〜！
This looks bad.
I doubt it's gonna let me escape.
ダメだ…
逃がしてくれる気は なさそうだ
But wait... This is nothing
compared to Veldora, is it?
待てよ
でも ヴェルドラに比べれば…
大したことなくね？
Maybe it's not as scary as I thought.
思ったより怖くないかも
I can do it!
いけそう！
Water Blade!
水刃！
わお！
That's a much stronger
technique than I expected.
想像以上に強力な技だな
I'll have to be careful who I use it on...
使う相手を考えないと…
Wait...
待てよ？
If I use Predator to eat
this snake and analyze it,
これ“捕食者”で捕食して
解析したら
wouldn't I be able to take its abilities?
この蛇の能力 奪えるんじゃね？
Right! Eat it whole!
ええい ままよ！
Blech!
おええ〜！
I can't taste things, but still! Blech!
って 味 感じないけど
おええ〜！
フウ…
Analysis complete.
（大賢者）
解析完了
スキル“毒霧吐息”
Skills: Poisonous Breath and
Sense Heat Source acquired.
Poisonous
Breath
Sense
Heat Source
Poisonous
Breath
Acquired
Sense
Heat Source
Acquired
“熱源感知”を獲得しました
You can now mimic Black Serpent.
（リムル）
あっ！　毒を吐き
周囲の熱反応を感知できる…
So I can breathe poison
and sense heat sources?
That could come in pretty handy.
これ 結構 便利じゃね？
Man, Predator sure is useful!
いやあ “捕食者”マジ使えるな！
All right! I'm gonna
acquire a lot more skills!
よし！
スキルをバンバン獲得するぞ！
Armorsaurus Appeared
Mimic Black Serpent
（リムル）くらえ！
Take this!
— Poisonous Breath —
"Body Armor" Acquired
I'd better not use Poisonous
Breath anymore...
毒霧吐息は封印しよう
Evil Centipede Appeared
（リムル）えい！
"Paralysis Breath" Acquired
Black Spider Appeared
（リムル）水刃 水刃 水刃 水刃！
Water Blade! Water Blade!
"Sticky Thread," and  "Steel Thread" Acquired
フウ…
あ〜ああ〜
Giant Bat Appeared
"Drain," and "Ultrasonic Wave" Acquired
（リムル）
あめんぼ あかいな あいうえお
A red water strider, A-I-U-E-O!
うきもに こえびも…
Little shrimp swim in the algae!
Using the organ that the bat
used for its Ultrasonic Wave,
（リムル）
コウモリの
超音波を発生させる器官を利用して
I was finally able to speak.
しゃべれるようにもなった
We are aliens.
ワレワレハ ウチュウジンデアル
Then, after several weeks of
wandering around that cave...
（リムル）
そして さまよい続けること数十日
ついに！
At last...
This is probably the exit, right?
多分 これが出口… だよな？
Well, now what?
さて どうしよう
水刃で切り刻めるかな？
Can I cut it up with Water Blade?
（ギド）ハア…
It finally opened.
（ギド）やっと開(ひら)きやしたぜ
It's so rusty, the keyhole's falling apart.
錆(さ)びついてしまって
鍵穴もボロボロでやす
That's no surprise.
（カバル）しかたないさ
Nobody's come in here for 300 years.
300年 誰も中に入ったことが
ないんだろ？
We won't be attacked out of nowhere, right?
（エレン）
いきなり襲われたり
しないですよね？
Of course, if it comes to it,
we can always use Escape...
（エレン）
まあ いざというときは
エスケープ 使いますけど…
The first humans I've seen...
（リムル）
初めて見る人間…
I don't know what they're here for,
but I guess they're adventurers?
何しにきたのか知らないけど
冒険者… かな？
Wait, I can understand them!
ていうか 言葉が分かるけど
Intention
Magic Sense
The use of Magic Sense turns sound waves
that carry intention into comprehensible words.
（大賢者）
解(かい)…
Answer.
The use of Magic Sense turns sound waves
that carry intention into comprehensible words.
So that's why. Thank goodness!
（リムル）
なるほど よかった
俺 英語 苦手だったんだよね
I was never good at English.
And by producing sound waves that
carry your thoughts, you can converse.
（大賢者）
逆に 思念を乗せて発声すれば
会話も可能です
Oh!
（リムル）
ほお…
でも 俺… 今 スライムだし
But I'm a slime now.
話しかけて
いきなり攻撃されても困るしな
It would suck if I talked to them
and they immediately attacked me.
All right, I'm gonna
activate my Stealth Arts.
（ギド）
じゃあ あっしの隠密アーツを
発動させやすよ
He called that skill "Stealth"?
You could peep all you wanted with that.
（リムル）
“隠密”って言ってたっけ
あのスキル…
のぞき見し放題だ
What a disgraceful creep!
けしからんヤツだ！
I'll have to make friends with him later!
あとで友達になる必要が
ありそうだな
Are they gone?
行ったか
What is it?
（ギド）どうしやした？
I thought I sensed a monster...
（エレン）
なんか魔物の気配を感じたんだけど
気のせいかな？
Was it my imagination?
So I left the cave.
（リムル）
俺は洞窟を出た
How long has it been since
I walked in the sunlight?
お天道(てんと)様の下を歩くのは
何日ぶりだろう
There's been no sign of Veldora since then.
あれから
ヴェルドラの反応は何もない
It seems like he vanished for good,
but I know that's not true.
消えてしまったかのようだが
そうではないことを俺は知っている
I promised, after all.
約束したからな
I'll have to build up a lot of funny stories
to tell him about next time we meet.
（リムル）
次に会ったとき 笑って話せる
面白おかしいエピソード
たくさん用意しておいてやろう
Ah, I haven't seen the outside in so long!
ああ… 久しぶりのシャバだ
The air tastes so sweet!
空気が うまい
Not that I can taste.
味覚ないけど…
Goblins Appeared
Hey, Veldora...
（リムル）
なあ ヴェルドラ…
It looks like I'm about to have one funny
story to tell you about already.
面白おかしいエピソードを
早速１つ用意できそうだよ
Scrawny bodies,
貧相な体つき
beat-up weapons...
ボロボロの武器
（リーダー）グガッ 強き者よ
Strong one, do you have business here?
この先に何か用事が
おありですか？
（リムル）
強き者？
Strong one?
う〜ん… って 俺？
Wait, me?
I just need to produce sound
waves carrying my thoughts?
（リムル）
思念を乗せて発声すればいいんだな
よし！
Okay!
Right, so, hello!
え〜っと！　はじめまして！
俺はスライムの
リムルという…
I'm a slime, and my name is Rimuru!
あなた様の力は
十分に分かりました！
We're well aware of how strong you are, sir!
Please, quiet your voice!
どうか 声を静めてください！
Maybe I thought too hard...
（リムル）
思念が強すぎたかな？
So, did you need something?
（小声で）で 俺に なんか用？
強力な魔物の気配がしたので
警戒に来たしだいです
We sensed a powerful monster,
so we came here as a precaution.
I don't sense anything like that.
（リムル）
そんなもの
俺には感じられないけど？
Surely you jest!
（リーダー）ご冗談を！
Even if you face us in that
form, we won't be fooled!
そのようなお姿をされていても
我々は だまされませんぞ！
I guess he really does mean me.
（リムル）
やっぱり 俺のことか…
強き者よ
Strong one, having seen your
power, we wish to ask a favor.
あなたを見込んで
お願いがあるのですが
Then I was led to the Goblin Village.
（リムル）
俺は ゴブリンの村に案内された
It sure is a shoddy village, though.
それにしても粗末な村だ
I bet Veldora could blow
it away with one snort.
ヴェルドラの鼻息で吹き飛びそう
Welcome, visitor.
（村長）ようこそ お客人…
I am the elder of this village.
（村長）
私は この村の村長を
させていただいております
Hi, nice to meet you.
（リムル）はい どうもよろしく
So, what favor did you want to ask of me?
で 自分にお願いとは 何ですか？
実は最近 魔物の動きが
Have you noticed that monsters
have been unusually active of late?
活発になっているのは
ご存じでしょうか？
No...
（リムル）いや…
Our god disappeared one month ago.
我らの神が ひと月前に
お姿を お隠しになられたのです
As a result, monsters in the area
have been continually harassing us.
そのため近隣の魔物が
この地に
ちょっかいをかけ始めまして…
Their god? Does he mean Veldora?
（リムル）
神って…
ヴェルドラのことか？
時期的には合うな
The timing fits.
I guess he was keeping monsters away?
魔物よけになっていたということか
We tried to fight them,
but we lack the numbers...
我々も応戦したのですが
戦力的に厳しく…
そ… それで あなた様に！
S-So we hoped you would...
...help you out, huh?
（リムル）
力を貸してほしいと…
But I'm just a slime.
（リムル）
しかし 自分 スライムですので
I doubt I can do all the
things you expect of me.
期待されているような働きは
できないと思うのですが
ハハハ ご謙遜を
Please, don't be modest.
ご謙遜を！
Don't be modest.
A mere slime would not
emit such an intense aura.
ただのスライムに
そこまでのオーラは出せませぬよ
You are quite a famous monster, are you not?
相当に名をはせる魔物なのでしょう
Aura?
（リムル）オーラ？
What's he talking about?
I don't have one of those.
（リムル）
何だ それ？
そんなの出した覚えはないぞ
Great Sage, change Magic Sense's perspective
大賢者 魔力感知の視点を切り替え
and let me look at myself.
自分を客観的に見せてくれ
Changing perspective.
（大賢者）
視点を切り替えます
Whoa! I've been emitting
an aura this whole time!
（リムル）
うわっ！
オーラを出したままだったのか
大通りを 社会の窓全開で
歩いていたみたいだ
I feel like I've been walking down
a major street with my fly open!
これは アカン！
This is bad!
So that's why the Goblins were scared of me!
だから ゴブリンたちは
おびえていたのか
（リムル）
フフフ… さすがは村長
分かるか？
Leave it to the elder to notice.
But of course. You cannot hide
the formidable air about you.
（村長）
もちろんでございますとも
漂う風格までは隠せておりませぬ
I see...
（リムル）
そうか 分かってしまったか
So you figured it out.
You guys show a lot of potential.
お前たちは
なかなか見どころがあるようだな
ふ〜ん！
Oh, I sucked it in.
おっ ひっこめられた
おお… 我々を
試されていたのですね
Ah... Have you been testing us?
It's fortunate that so many of
us were frightened by your aura.
そのオーラに おびえる者も
多かったもので助かります
Y-Yeah, that's right!
（リムル）そ… そうだな
You've got potential if you
can talk to me without fear!
おびえずに話しかけてくるとは
見どころがあるぞ
What potential?!
（リムル）
何の見どころだよ！
Come to think of it, how did those
humans in the cave not see my aura?
ていうか 洞窟にいた人間たち
よく気が付かなかったな
Are those guys okay?
あいつら 大丈夫か？
Thank you so much.
（村長）
ハハ… ありがとうございます
Ah, as for the favor we wish to ask...
あっ それで
お願いといいますのは…
According to the Goblins,
（リムル）
ゴブリンの話によると
wolf monsters, Direwolves,
attacked them from the east,
東の地からオオカミの魔物
牙狼族(がろうぞく)が押し寄せて 戦いになり
and many Goblins died in the ensuing battle.
ゴブリンの戦士が
多数 討ち死にしたのだという
Apparently, Direwolves are so much
more powerful than Goblins that
本来 牙狼族１匹に対して
ゴブリン10匹でかかっても
it takes ten Goblins to even have
a chance at beating one Direwolf.
勝てるかどうかの戦力差が
あるのだそうだ
And there was one warrior among them with
a name, who served as their guardian.
その中に 名持ちの守護者のような
戦士がいたのだという
Even that warrior was killed,
leaving the village in peril.
その戦士も討ち死にし
村は危機に瀕(ひん)している…
ということだった
牙狼族は全部で100匹程度
There are about 100 Direwolves in total.
How many do we have?
（リムル）こっちの戦力は？
Including females, we have
about 60 who can fight.
（村長）
戦えるのは
雌も合わせて60匹ぐらい
That's a pretty devastating
difference in strength.
（リムル）
絶望的な戦力差だな…
なんか無理ゲーっぽいな
It's like an impossible video game.
So did that Goblin warrior fight
them knowing he couldn't win?
（リムル）
その名持ちのゴブリンの戦士は
勝てないと分かっていて
戦ったのか？
いえ… 牙狼族の情報は
No... That warrior gave
his life just retrieving
information on the Direwolves for us.
その戦士が命懸けで
入手したものなのです
戦士は私の息子で
The warrior was my son,
and his elder brother.
これの兄でした
I see...
（リムル）
そうか… 悪いことを聞いた
Forgive me for asking that.
Elder, tell me one thing.
（リムル）村長 １つ確認したい
Y-Yes?
（村長）は… はい
What will I get in return
for helping this village?
（リムル）
俺が この村を助けるなら
その見返りは何だ？
What can you guys give me?
お前たちは俺に何を差し出せる？
I'm not actually looking for compensation.
（リムル）
本当は見返りなんて求めてない
I just need to put on a bit of a show.
ただ ちょっと体裁を
整える必要があるだけだ
わ… 我々の忠誠をささげます！
W-We will offer you our loyalty!
Please grant us your protection!
我らに守護を
お与えください
If you do, we will swear our loyalty to you!
さすれば我らは
リムル様に
忠誠を誓いましょう！
We will swear!
（リーダー）誓いましょう！
This looks familiar.
（リムル）
懐かしいな…
Senpai! Just this once, please!
（田村(たむら)）
先輩！　今回だけ お願いします！
Oh, all right.
（三上(みかみ)）しょうがねえなあ
When all is said and done,
I just can't say no.
（リムル）
なんのかんの言って
俺は頼まれ事に弱かった
が… 牙狼族だ！
Th-The Direwolves!
This is terrible!
ヤバいよ ヤバいよ！
おしまいだ〜！
We're done for!
We'll all be eaten!
俺たち 食われちゃうんだ〜！
Let's run!
（ゴブリンたち）
逃げようよ！
ど… どこへ？
B-But where?
（村長）
お… お前たち 落ち着きなさい
E-Everyone, please calm down.
There's no need to fear.
（リムル）ビビる必要はない
We're going to defeat them.
（リムル）これから倒す相手だ
おお　でっ では…
Y-You mean...
In lieu of the Storm Dragon Veldora,
（リムル）
お前たちの その願い
暴風竜ヴェルドラに代わり
I, Rimuru Tempest, will grant your wish!
このリムル＝テンペストが
聞き届けよう！
Thank you so much!
ありがとうございます
We are your loyal servants, great Rimuru!
我々は リムル様の
忠実なるしもべでございます
You can count on me.
（リムル）任せておけ
And that's how I became the Goblins' leader,
（リムル）
こうして俺は ゴブリンたちの主(あるじ)…
their guardian.
守護者となったのだった
Next time, "Battle at the Goblin Village."
（大賢者）
次回「ゴブリン村での戦い」
Battle at the Goblin Village